A Register of the Albert J. and Roberta Wohlstetter Papers
Hoover Institution Archives
- Speeches and Writings, 1936-1996. (Box 62)
  - Notes by Albert Wohlstetter., See also Speeches and Writings/Writings
    - "Pranger-Tahtinen on Israel Population Attacks and Sophisticated Weaponry,", 1975 August 9 (Folder 115: 12)
    - "Nuclear Exports Policy, Scoville, and the Essential Irrelevance of Safeguards,", 1975 August 10 (Folder 115: 13)
    - On comments by Raymond Aron, Kenneth Hunt, Tonne Huitfeldt, and Mile Momoi on missing topics and supplementary perspectives and questions, 1975 September 16 (Folder 115: 14)
    - "Relating Policy to the Problem of Critical Time that Is Shrinking Without Any Necessary Breaking of the Rules,", 1975 September 16. (Folder 115: 15)
      Includes a revised version, 1975 November 14
    - "Beyond International Safeguards,", 1975 September 23 (Folder 115: 16)
    - "The Shrinking Critical Time to Make Explosives,", 1975 December 1 (Folder 115: 17)
    - "History of U.S.-S.U. Arms Competition," and notes on May-Steinbrunner-Wolfe manuscript, 1976 April. (Folder 115: 18)
      Includes comments on the draft chapters of the history of the United States-Soviet Union arms competition by H. Rowen
    - "The Development of Nuclear Capabilities in 4th Countries: Likelihood and Consequences,", 1976 May 2 (Folder 115: 19)
    - "Substitution Tarapur,", 1976 July 11 (Folder 115: 20)
    - "Indian Peaceful Use Constraint Violation, Unilateral Understandings, Safeguards etc.,", 1976 July 17 (Folder 115: 21)
    - On Indian forecasts of nuclear and other energy demands, 1976 July 20 (Folder 115: 22)
    - "Note On Reliability, Unreliability, Arbitrariness, Sanctions and Constraints on Nuclear Exports,", 1976 July 28 (Folder 115: 23)
    - "To Proliferation Group: Breeder Sales to Third World to Keep European Nuclear Industry Alive,", 1976 September 5 (Folder 115: 24)
    - "Energy Information, Entropy and the Future of Photovoltaics,", 1976 November 11 (Folder 115: 25)
    - "Key Points on Non-Proliferation Policy (with Harry Rowen), 1977 March 14 (Folder 115: 26)
    - "Why the Importance of Plutonium Fuel Was Overestimated,", 1977 May 8 (Folder 115: 27)
    - "Rate of Discount in the Nuclear Energy Programs Here and Abroad,", 1977 May 21 (Folder 115: 28)
    - "India against Pakistan's Reprocessing" (with Roberta Wohlstetter), 1977 June 27 (Folder 115: 29)
    - "Civilian Noise, Response to Timely Military Signals, and the Influence of Incremental Costs, Incremental Time, and Incremental Risks on the Decision to Acquire Nuclear Weapons" (with Roberta Wohlstetter), 1977 August 20 (Folder 115: 30)
    - "Iran-Turkey Relations and the Ethnic Minority Problems" (with Roberta Wohlstetter), 1977 September (Folder 115: 31)
    - "Breeder Predictions,", 1978 January 10 (Folder 115: 32)
    - On interdependence for ACDA and on predictions, 1978 March 19 (Folder 115: 33)
    - "Metallic Plutonium, Article IV, and Articles I and II of the Nuclear Proliferation Treaty,", 1978 March 21 (Folder 115: 34)
    - "The Indian Bomb and Nuclear Electricity,", 1978 May 3 (Folder 115: 35)
    - "Was the CIRUS Reactor Empty or Non-Empty or Neither Empty Nor Non-Empty of American Heavy Water?", 1978 July 13 (Folder 115: 36)
    - For outline of paper on uranium and plutonium for Bunge, 1978 November 29 (Folder 115: 37)
    - Note for INFCE, 1979 January 2 (Folder 115: 38)
    - "Note on Self-Confirming vs. Self-Annihilating Sentences,", 1979 March 27 (Folder 115: 39)
    - "Notes on Signals Hidden in Noise,", 1979 April 6 (Folder 115: 40)
    - "Note on Dispersal of Navy Firepower and More Ships: Increments to Navy Budgets and Admiral Hayward,", 1979 April 14 (Folder 115: 41)
    - "Comparing American and Soviet Ability to Project Power,", 1979 June 8 (Box-folder 116: 1)
    - "Economic Aid, Like Military Aid, Can Have Perverse Effects,", 1979 June 8 (Folder 116: 2)
    - "On CEQ proposal" (with Harry Rowen), 1979 August 25 (Folder 116: 3)
    - "Russian Use of Airspace,", 1979 November 12 (Folder 116: 4)
    - "FSU Choice between Ferrying Fighters or Lifting Them Disassembled by Air or Sea,", 1979 November 13 (Folder 116: 5)
    - "On Need for Stressing Turkish Facilities among the Many Alternatives in or near the Region Which Should Be Pursued,", 1980 January 23 (Folder 116: 6)
    - "Indian and Iraqi Evenhandedness in the Persian Gulf Area of the Indian Ocean,", 1980 February 4 (Folder 116: 7)
    - "Two Points on Long-Term and Short-Term Options,", 1980 February 4. (Folder 116: 8)
      Includes a typescript version entitled "Two Points on Long Term and Interim Measures and on Long and Short Term Interests," 1980 February 18
    - On the incompatibility of early decisions during the Truman administration, 1980 February 18 (Folder 116: 9)
    - "Europe and the Confused Signals from Washington after Afghanistan, 1980 February 24 (Folder 116: 10)
    - "Vogt Combat Radii of Fighters Available for the Strike and Intercept Mission in the Upper Gulf,", 1980 April 18 (Folder 116: 11)
    - "BDM's Lellenberg on the Rapid Deployment Force and the NATO Center and Uwe and other Europeans,", 1980 May 20 (Folder 116: 12)
    - "Jim Patton's Sea-Strike Pacific Briefing,", 1980 May 20 (Folder 116: 13)
    - "Mac Bundy, the State Department and India,", 1980 June 15 (Folder 116: 14)
    - "Wealth Transfers vs. Income Losses as a Result of Political or Military Changes in the Gulf,", 1980 October 1 (Folder 116: 15)
    - On Henry Kissinger and SALT, 1980 November 15 (Folder 116: 16)
    - On rumored indications that Iraq might be interested in partitioning Iran, 1980 November 15 (Folder 116: 17)
    - "Overall Demand for AWACs in Widely Separated Theaters,", 1980 December 4 (Folder 116: 18)
    - "Note on a Strategy for the Japanese to Protect National and Alliance Interests in the Gulf,", 1981 January 30. (Folder 116: 19)
      Includes revised version, 1981 February 2
    - "Cuban Contingencies and Matching US Responses,", 1981 February 1 (Folder 116: 20)
    - On the Armenian secret army and Soviet expansion in eastern Turkey, 1981 February 1 (Folder 116: 21)
    - "National Intelligence Spending Compared to Defense Spending, 1962-1976 and 1964-1980,", 1981 February 20 (Folder 116: 22)
    - "The Soviet Threat: Djilas vs. Kennan on the Role of the Red Army in Imposing Soviet Communism,", 1981 March 8 (Folder 116: 23)
    - "Biases in Comparing U.S.-S.U. Defense Budget Trends: The Volunteer Force,", 1981 March 18 (Folder 116: 24)
    - "Notes on Security Assistance for Future Memoranda to Fred Ikle,", 1981 April 6 (Folder 116: 25)
    - "Israeli-Iraq Reactor,", 1981 June 18 (Folder 116: 26)
    - "Notes on Western Assumptions about Soviet Objectives and Behavior in Arms Agreements,", 1981 August 11 (Folder 116: 27)
    - "Policy Guidance,", 1981 October-November (Folder 116: 28)
    - On Rapporteur's analytic summary of workshop on Internal and External Factors in Soviet Behavior: Implications for the West, John Van Oudenaren, 1981 October 19 (Folder 116: 29)
    - "Helmut Schmidt Pleads for Clemency as an Orphan,", 1981 November 25 (Folder 116: 30)
    - "New U.S. Facilities in Turkey to Replace Our Bases in Greece and as an Aid to Tourism in Turkey,", 1981 November 25 (Folder 116: 31)
    - "Policy Predisposition, Influence Conscious and Unconscious Perceptions of Failure to Perceive Signals,", 1981 December 3 (Folder 116: 32)
    - "Notes on the Two Way Link between the Rise in Neutralism and Arms Control," revised, 1981 December 8 (Folder 116: 33)
    - "Restraint and the Defense of Europe,", 1981 December 28 (Folder 116: 34)
    - On Armenian terrorists and Turkey, 1981-1982 (Folder 116: 35)
    - "The Role of Terror in the Destabilization of Turkey," revised, 1982 January 6 and February 26 (Folder 116: 36)
    - "Their Pain and Ours in Far and Close Prospects: Economic, Political, and Military Parallel and Interactions,", 1982 January 7 (Folder 116: 37)
    - "The Polish Crisis, Economic Sanctions in the Long Run, Military Competition between the East and the West,", 1982 January 12 (Folder 116: 38)
    - "Interpretation of Crisis, Before, During, and After,", 1982 February 1 (Box-folder 117: 1)
    - "Some Aspects of Cuban Missile Crisis Which Are Applicable Today,", 1982 February 1 (Folder 117: 2)
    - "Tomahawk Cruise Missile Overview,", 1982 February 12 (Folder 117: 3)
    - On cruise missiles, 1982 February 23 (Folder 117: 4)
    - "Negotiated Coalitions or Elections,", 1982 February 28 (Folder 117: 5)
    - "Western Subsidized Export Credits and Cultural Exchanges with the CMEA and Alliance Defense,", 1982 March 23 (Folder 117: 6)
    - "McCone's Reasoning that the Soviets Would Install Offensive Missiles in Cuba and, Later that They Were in the Process,", 1982 April 10 (Folder 117: 7)
    - "Some Untidiness in Resolution of the Cuban Missile Crisis,", 1982 April 12 (Folder 117: 8)
    - "How Calling in Polish Loans Differs From Other Economic Sanctions, So Far As Our Allies Are Concerned,", 1982 April 21 (Folder 117: 9)
    - On Inserts and Revisions for Brian Chow's Japan U.S. cooperation etc., 1982 May 6 (Folder 117: 10)
    - "Korea 1946-1982: Notes on the Problem of Responding to Ambiguous Signals,", 1982 May 12 (Folder 117: 11)
    - "Threats in Korea 1946-1982: Enemy Aims, Intentions, Capabilities,", 1982 May 12 (Folder 117: 12)
    - "On Four Major Types of Situation for Which We Will Want to Get and Respond to Warning,", 1982 May 21 (Folder 117: 13)
    - "Regions and Contingencies Needing Attention: The Big War in the Center and Off-Center Contingencies,", 1982 May 22 (Folder 117: 14)
    - Notes dictated by Albert Wohlstetter from Nancy Virts's notes on Korea, 1982 May 25 (Folder 117: 15)
    - On improved technology, 1982 June-July (Folder 117: 16)
    - "The Problem of Technology Transfer from the DOD and DOE Laboratories and Research Agencies to Our Services,", 1982 June 2 (Folder 117: 17)
    - "Notes on Sonnenfeldt/Kissinger Doctrine,", 1982 June 23. (Folder 117: 18)
    - For proposal to Admiral Kollmorgen on concept formulation for range-insensitive, extremely precise delivery systems and the complementary technologies, 1982 July 11 (Folder 117: 19)
    - "Outline for a DOD-Wide Two Year Program on the New Defense Policy and New Technologies,", 1982 July 22 (Folder 117: 20)
    - "More All-Purpose Pseudo-Statistical Arguments Involving 'Infinity',", 1982 August 29 (Folder 117: 21)
    - "Notes on Wartime Challenges to Soviet Control,", 1982 October 22 (Folder 117: 22)
    - "Oppenheimer, the Trinity Bomb, and John Donne,", 1983 January 21 (Folder 117: 23)
    - "Stability, Imprecision, and Arms Agreements,", 1983 March 1 (Folder 117: 24)
    - On meeting Soviet challenges in the third world, 1983 April 8 (Folder 117: 25)
    - "A Note on the Costs and Horrors of Conventional War,", 1983 July 16 (Folder 117: 26)
    - "A Note on Mort Halperin's 'Clever Briefers, Etc.',", 1983 September 19 (Folder 117: 27)
    - "Note on Soviet Power and Western Disarmament: Apparent Increases in Soviet Power Tend to Generate Western Resistance to Western Increments in Power,", 1983 September 19 (Folder 117: 28)
    - "U.S. and Soviet Alternative Risks in What's Needed to Deter U.S. Compared to What's Needed to Deter the Soviets,", 1983 October. (Box-folder 118: 1)
      Note for Commentary
    - "Very Preliminary Notes on Global Atmospheric Consequences of Nuclear War,", 1983 December 12 (Folder 118: 2)
    - "Note on Richard Brody's January 10 Memoranda on Deterrence and Warning,", 1984 January? (Folder 118: 3)
    - "Note on the Refinement of the Dual Criterion and Its Expanded Operational Application, and on Indexes of Mass Destruction,", 1984 January 29-30 (Folder 118: 4)
    - "On the Interpretation of Soviet Exercises,", 1984 July 18 (Folder 118: 5)
    - "Notes for Bud and for RW/AW on Arms Agreements,", 1984 August 25 (Folder 118: 6)
    - Notes on qualitative disarmament and SALT, 1984 September 28 (Folder 118: 7)
    - "Notes for: Major Issues of Nuclear Strategy,", 1984 October 11 (Folder 118: 8)
    - "Notes for Revising Origin of Second Strike Theory,", 1984 November 9 (Folder 118: 9)
    - "Nuclear Boomerangs and Retaliation in Kind,", 1985 January 29 (Folder 118: 10)
    - "Intercontinental LNOs Avoiding Silos in US Z1," revised, 1985 April 21 (Folder 118: 11)
    - On MAD and the transformation of strategic bombing, 1985 April 24 (Folder 118: 12)
    - "Working Note on Zen Targeting,", 1985 May 13 (Folder 118: 13)
    - "Notes While Reading Greg Canavan, Simple Discussion of the Stability,", 1985 May 15 (Folder 118: 14)
    - "Arms Agreements to Destabilize the Difference between U.S. and S.U. Arms Postures,", 1985 May 20 (Folder 118: 15)
    - "On Arms Control: What We Should Look For in an Arms Agreement" (with Roberta Wohlstetter), 1985 May 20 (Folder 118: 16)
    - "Two Ways of Looking at Stability,", 1985 June 14 (Folder 118: 17)
    - "Notes for a Modest Revision of 'Dissent in the Soviet Empire',", 1985 July 29 (Folder 118: 18)
    - For comments and suggestions on 6 August draft on "Long Term Development, etc.,", 1985 August 15 (Folder 118: 19)
    - "Draft Answer to the Question: Why the Soviets Might Want to Negotiate for or to Complete an Agreement on Self-Defense Zones?", 1985 August 29 (Folder 118: 20)
    - "U.S.-S.U. May 1971 Statement on Linking Offense and Defense and the SU Destruction of SALT I,", 1985 October 21 (Folder 118: 21)
    - "Devolution of Command, MAD and the Constitution,", 1985 December 7 (Folder 118: 22)
    - "Recovering Communication after an Attack,", 1985 December 7 (Folder 118: 23)
    - "Note on Disclosure Policy: Press Reports on Ivy League" (with Roberta Wohlstetter), 1986 February 5 (Folder 118: 24)
    - "Robert McNamara and Hans Bethe on Nuclear War,", 1986 February 26 (Folder 118: 25)
    - "Note on Boomerang of Blackout and EMP Attacks in the Theater?", 1986 March 18 (Folder 118: 26)
    - "Army Neglect of C3 Vulnerability - 1962,", 1986 March 19 (Folder 118: 27)
    - "How to Get or not to Get Bilateral Arms Control: Lessons of the Lessons Drawn from the Test Moratorium of 1958-61" (with Roberta Wohlstetter), 1986 March 19 (Folder 118: 28)
    - "McG Bundy Memo to JFK on Controlling Decision to Use Nuclear Weapons,", 1986 April 4 (Folder 118: 29)
    - "Notes on New Seismic Arrays and the Proofs of Noncompliance with a Comprehensive Test Ban,", 1986 April 7 (Folder 118: 30)
    - "S.U. C3I vs. U.S. C3I,", 1986 April 7 (Folder 118: 31)
    - "Incompatible Aims and Claims of CTB Proponents,", 1986 April 8 (Folder 118: 32)
    - "In-S.U. Network of Arrays and Moratoria: Then and Now,", 1986 April 8 (Box-folder 119: 1)
    - "Postponing Unilateral Defense Indefinitely Because a Temporary Postponement Was Violated,", 1986 April 9 (Folder 119: 2)
    - "Deep Underground Command Posts, Earth Penetrators, and Location Uncertainty," revised, 1986 April 11 (Folder 119: 3)
    - "Versatility of Deep and Shallow Earth Penetrators,", 1986 April 11 (Folder 119: 4)
    - "The Press and National Security Secrets,", 1986 May 26 (Folder 119: 5)
    - "On Distributed Sensors for NOCC Chapter,", 1986 May 28 (Folder 119: 6)
    - "Reasons for the Lag,", 1986 July 23 (Folder 119: 7)
    - "Testing, SDI, and the Luddite Trend in Arms Control,", 1986 September 16 (Folder 119: 8)
    - "Notes on Exercises and Their Relation to Decisions on the Conduct of War, 1986 September 25 (Folder 119: 9)
    - "Note on High Resolution Satellite Photography and the Press,", 1986 November 10 (Folder 119: 10)
    - "What We Say and What We Do,", 1986 November 17 (Folder 119: 11)
    - Notes on Iran, 1987 January 16. (Folder 119: 12)
    - "Notes on Iraq-Iran War as of February 12, 1987,", 1987 February 12 (Folder 119: 13)
    - "Note on the Graphic Presentation of Trees for Future Soviet Options against France and Future French Options for Reply,", 1987 May 19 (Folder 119: 14)
    - "Discontinuities, Breakthroughs and Cumulatively Revolutionary Gradual Change,", 1987 May 28 (Folder 119: 15)
    - "Notes on the Dulles-Eisenhower 'New Look' on Reading Townsend Hoopes' The Devil and John Foster Dulles,", 1988 January 7 (Folder 119: 16)
    - "Note on Chaban Delmas,", 1988 January 23 (Folder 119: 17)
    - "Some Familiar Bureaucratic Views on the 'Verification Problem' for Arms Agreements and Specifically for START,", 1988 March 11 (Folder 119: 18)
    - "Soviets Agree With Western Nuclear Disarmers that Conventional War Would Be as Bad as Nuclear War,", 1988 April 22 (Folder 119: 19)
    - "Soviets Still Threatening Nuclear Winter to Beat SDI,", 1988 April 22 (Folder 119: 20)
    - On Kennedy, 1988 May 17 (Folder 119: 21)
    - "Comprehensive Outline: The Uprise of Our (Relative) Downfall,", 1988 May 20 (Folder 119: 22)
    - "Points on Kennedy and Other Proponents of the Imperial Overstretch Argument,", 1988 May 24 (Folder 119: 23)
    - "Kennedy on His Misinterpreters,", 1988 June 23 (Folder 119: 24)
    - "Notes for the Overall White Paper on the Interactions among Arms Control, New Technologies, Nuclear Policy, Integrated Coalitions Strategy, etc.,", 1988 July 20 (Folder 119: 25)
    - "Acceptable Growth Rates: Hatsopoulos, Krugman, and Summers,", 1988 August 1 (Folder 119: 26)
    - "Has US Income Per Family or Per Person Improved Since 1967?", 1988 September 7 (Folder 119: 27)
    - On measured growth and environmental investments and Robert Solow's Nobel speech of June 1988 in American Economic Review, 1988 September 8 (Folder 119: 28)
    - "Measuring and Comparing GDPs and Their Component Aggregates across Countries and across Time,", 1988 September 14 (Folder 119: 29)
    - "Note on June O'Neill's Commission on Civil Rights Study of Male Black to White Ratios at Deciles,", 1988 September 26 (Folder 119: 30)
    - "Note on Mancur Olson for New Republic Article,", 1988 September 30 (Folder 119: 31)
    - "Adjusting Ratios at Quantiles and Ratios of Their Means to Make the Proper Deflation with the Corrected or Experimental CPI,", 1988 October 14 (Folder 119: 32)
    - "Relative and Absolute Income Improvements Since Paleolithic Man,", 1988 November 2 (Folder 119: 33)
    - "ASATS to Defend the Midgetman,", 1989 July 20 (Folder 119: 34)
    - "Note on Misunderstandings of Brilliant Pebbles in a Briefing on Strategic Defense Issues Responding to a Request from SecDef Cheney,", 1989 August 7 (Folder 119: 35)
    - "Equality vs. Equity and the Public Good in the French Revolution,", 1989 August 16 (Folder 119: 36)
    - "Note on Chalmers Johnson and David Brock Illustrating and Describing Japan Bashing,", 1989 October 3 (Folder 119: 37)
    - "Does the International Division of Labor Even Among Allies Endanger National Security or Our Economic Well-Being?", 1989 November 13 (Box-folder 120: 1)
    - "Notes For a Possible OpEd Piece on Prudence and Malta,", 1989 November 28 (Folder 120: 2)
    - "Plausible and Implausible Contingencies and Strategic Aims, in Foreign Economic Policy,", 1989 December 12 (Folder 120: 3)
    - "Notes for PW on Response of Defense Planning to the Drastic Changes in the Strategic Environment,", 1990 January 22 (Folder 120: 4)
    - "Are the Poor Getting Poorer and the Rich Richer?" (with Nancy Virts), 1990 February 6 (Folder 120: 5)
    - "Aristotle vs. Plato on Inequality and Private Property,", 1990 May 14 (Folder 120: 6)
    - "Munich and Lithuania: Rabbits that Cause All the Trouble,", 1990 May 14 (Folder 120: 7)
    - "Innovation, Growth and the Visible Dead Hand of Bureaucracy,", 1990 June 4 (Folder 120: 8)
    - "Gorbachev, the KGB and the Freeing of East Europe,", 1990 June 22 (Folder 120: 9)
    - "East Europe's Move towards Free Markets and EEC,", 1990 June 28 (Folder 120: 10)
    - "The KGB and East Europe in Elections and Western Surprise,", 1990 June 28 (Folder 120: 11)
    - "Note for 'History of Strategy' on Soviet Control of Nuclear Weapons: Unclassified Soviet References Used in R. Tarleton Briefing, 31 July 1990,", 1990 August 7 (Folder 120: 12)
    - For suggestions on graphics in assessments of selected allied options, 1990 October 9 (Folder 120: 13)
    - "Convincing Saddam the Coalition Has the Will to Use Force,", 1990 December 27 (Folder 120: 14)
    - "Shaping Precise Means to Clear-Cut Ends in the Gulf," with Fred Hoffman, 1991 January 2 (Folder 120: 15)
    - "Attacking Water Trucks at Night with F-117s: Unclassified Note,", 1991 January 7 (Folder 120: 16)
    - "The SASC Hearings Showed the Domestic Consensus Hadn't Lasted, not Its Durability,", 1991 January 9 (Folder 120: 17)
    - "Evening the Odds for the Iraqi Resistance,", 1991 March 28 (Folder 120: 18)
    - "Christine Helms on August 13, 1990 on Bush's Covert Strategy,", 1991 April 4. (Folder 120: 19)
      Includes notes on "Christine Helms and Other Experts on Iraq," 1991 April 4
    - "C3 in the Gulf War, and Curbing Software Exports,", 1991 May 24 (Folder 120: 20)
    - "The Information Revolution Brings to an End Nearly Two Centuries of 'Total War',", 1991 May 24 (Folder 120: 21)
    - "Bush on Supposed Success in Ruining Saddam's Mass Destruction Threat,", 1991 July 31 (Folder 120: 22)
    - "Iraqi Nuclear Weapons, Desert Storm, and the Aftermath,", 1991 September 27 (Folder 120: 23)
    - "Don Rice's Air Force Perspective on Desert Storm,", 1991 October 4 (Folder 120: 24)
    - "Mathematics and RAND in the 1950s,", 1991 October 18 (Folder 120: 25)
    - "Transaction Costs, Ronald Coase, and Innovation,", 1991 October 18 (Folder 120: 26)
    - "Diversity in Interaction at the 1950s RAND,", 1991 October 24 (Folder 120: 27)
    - "Harold Larndner,", 1991 October 24 (Folder 120: 28)
    - "Rededicated But Lost: Western Leaders Failed,", 1991 October 28 (Folder 120: 29)
    - "Signals of the Coup, the Impossibility of 'Reform,' and the Collapse of Communist Economy" (with Roberta Wohlstetter), 1991 October 28 (Folder 120: 30)
    - "Anders Aslund's Ph.D. Thesis on Gorbachev's Economic Reform,", 1991 November 11 (Folder 120: 31)
    - "Richard's Suggestion for Roberta,", 1991 November 25 (Folder 120: 32)
    - "Unpersuasive U.S. Responses July 1990 to Iraq's Signals on Q8 Invasion" (with Roberta Wohlstetter), 1992 January 16 (Folder 120: 33)
    - On Baker Fog on Russian nuclear weapons, 1992 January 20 (Folder 120: 34)
    - "Cooperating with Former Adversaries on Ballistic Missile Defense,", 1992 January 31 (Folder 120: 35)
    - "Kedourie on Nationalism and the Split of the Old SU into Independent States,", 1992 January 31 (Folder 120: 36)
    - "Nuclear Triggers and Safety Catches, the 'FSU' and the 'FSRs',", 1992 February 6. (Box-folder 121: 1)
      Includes a note entitled, "Nuclear Triggers and Safety Catches in FSRs (Former Soviet Republics)," 1992 January 20. Includes related materials
    - "Nuclear Weapons and Kazakhstan versus the General Staff or Russia,", 1992 February 28 (Folder 121: 2)
    - "The Army and the Predominance of Prussia in the First Reich,", 1992 March 12 (Folder 121: 3)
    - "Kravchuk Offers an Opportunity for US to Clarify Ukrainian Monitoring of the Storage or Destruction of the Old Soviet Strategic Forces,", 1992 March 12 (Folder 121: 4)
    - "Old KGB Alive and Well in Post-Soviet Russia,", 1992 March 12 (Folder 121: 5)
    - "The Future of Arms and Freedom in the Old USSR,", 1992 March 17 (Folder 121: 6)
    - "PKK Terror (and Kohl/Saddam/Assad) vs. Turkey and Iraqi Kurds,", 1992 March 30 (Folder 121: 7)
    - "The Soviets on Atomic Energy before Joe-1,", 1992 March 30 (Folder 121: 8)
    - "Muffing the Chance of the Century?", 1992 April 16 (Folder 121: 9)
    - "Markets, Democracy and the Information Revolution,", 1992 June 4 (Folder 121: 10)
    - "The Information Revolution, Lanchester as a Rough Guide to Design Rather Than Prediction, and the Gulf War,", 1992 July 3 (Folder 121: 11)